Excuse me, man. Quick question for
you. Is this your Rolls Royce?
Yeah, yes, sir.
What do you do for a living?
This will be my 11th year in
the NFL. My name is Tavon Austin.
So what has been the most amount of
money that you ever made in a single year?
Multiple, multiple seven figures.
The business, 60 million, and then
a couple of million for myself.
I probably made 11 million.
In my last role, I was the chief
operating officer for a $700 million business called
Health Management Systems.
And did you guys end up selling your company?
We did. We sold it to
a private equity company for about...
Dallas, Texas is a top 20 city
in the entire world with the most millionaires.
We're out in Highland Park, Dallas, Texas,
the wealthiest area in all of Dallas,
asking multi-millionaires and luxury
shoppers how they became successful.
My first question, sir, what industry did
you decide to pursue a career in?
Consumer products industry.
Are you a business owner by any chance?
I am not.
You're not?
I'm the CEO of Frito-Lay.
You're the CEO of Frito?
Yeah.
You're the CEO of Frito-Lay?
That is incredible.
I mean, seriously.
I mean, you guys have great tips, obviously.
What's your best advice to anybody out there that's
trying to build a company into a company like Frito-Lay?
Wow.
Well, sky's the limit.
I mean, you can do anything.
Frito-Lay started with one man, Herman Lay.
Yeah.
Right?
Selling potato chips out of a truck.
Hustled, worked hard, did it the right way, took
care of his customers, took care of his employees.
And the next thing you
know, it's a multi-billion dollar business.
Yeah.
In today's environment.
You've got to, one, understand your consumer.
Who's buying your product better than anybody else?
Technology is the way to make sure that you stay
on top of consumer trends and you understand what consumers want.
Being consumer obsessed is, I
think, the most important thing.
Now, what was the biggest driving factor of your success that
enabled you to become a CEO of a multi-billion dollar company?
Hey, preparation and a little bit of luck, man.
Right place, right time.
Doing it the right way.
Being authentic.
Treating people like you want to be treated.
I mean, it really is.
You've got to be smart.
Everybody's got to be smart.
You've got to want to hustle.
Right?
You've got to want to work harder than the next guy, but
you can do all that and be a jerk and be failed.
That's the CEO of Frito-Lay
chips that we just interviewed, bro.
You can't make this shit up, bro.
I mean, we were just walking around in Dallas.
We sued the man and asked him a few questions.
He's the CEO of a multi-billion dollar company.
Let's keep going to get some more, man.
Shout out, Dallas.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
I decided to go into the retail business.
The retail business?
What did you do exactly?
Well, I ran a lot of different...
I ran a lot of different retail companies.
And what company were you the CEO of?
Well, I was a lot of them.
I was a penny company, the
pennies company, Macy company, Barneys, Neiman Marcus.
So a lot of different companies
that had difficulties at the time.
I was the CEO of the company, but
it's not the CEO who makes a success.
It's the people who work for that company, but it's the CEO's
responsibility to make those people realize how important they are to the company.
It's not one person.
In one minute, tell me the blueprint that it
takes to run a successful company, a multi-hundred-million-dollar company.
What's the blueprint to creating a strong...
A strong company in today's world?
Understanding the culture.
Understanding the culture of the company.
Each company is different.
Neiman Marcus is different than the penny company.
So you have to go in, you have
to understand who they are, not who you are.
And then you also got to understand your customer.
Because the number one thing that a person running a company has to know who his
customer is and take care of them and make sure your people are taken care of.
And then if you do that,
you can take care of the shareholder.
Even though people say the shareholder comes first, the
shareholder does come first because they can fire you.
But if you don't get...
If you don't take care of the customer first...
You're never going to take care of the shareholder.
Yo, my man we just interviewed right there was
the CEO of Petty's, Macy's and Neiman Marcus, bro.
I couldn't hold it together, bro.
We just interviewed the CEO of Frito-Lay
and now we're going to be that mogul.
That is a retail mogul right there.
Just dropped some straight game on
some serious entrepreneurship business advice, man.
Dallas, Texas has been fucking insane, bro.
Let's keep it going.
My first question for you, man.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
I'm a professional football player.
Professional football player?
Yeah.
What team do you play for?
I've played for several teams.
And hopefully this will be my level game.
NFL.
My name is Tavon Austin.
So I play for the Rams, Cowboys, Jacksonville.
Bills for a little bit and Green Bay.
West Virginia University.
You Tavon Austin?
Yes, sir.
Oh my goodness.
That is amazing.
This is crazy to me.
I go to UT, so we're
a little bit of a rival here.
Okay, yeah, yeah.
You all bust y'all up.
I know you did.
And trust me, I've seen your returns though.
I know you got it.
So I guess I'll ask you, man.
What's been the biggest driving factor of your
success that's enabled you to become a professional athlete?
Work your way into the NFL.
What does it take?
For number one, it takes a
lot of discipline and hard work.
I come from a place where a
lot of us don't really make it out.
You know what I mean?
So my mindset is different.
I want it better for myself.
I want it better for my family.
So with that being said, always stay focused.
Always seeing the point.
You got to have good people around you
that's willing to tell you when you're wrong.
You can't have no type of yes man around you.
You got to have stand up strong people,
either a woman or a man around you.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
Probably me, $11 million.
$11 million?
Yeah, $11 million.
What's your best financial advice to the young man?
To the younger generation out there?
Honestly, you got to get
the right financial advisor around you.
You got to get people.
Even though it's your money, you got to have
people carry it like it's their money as well.
You know what I mean?
Because you like nice things you'll spend, but
you need somebody that's going to be that backbone.
To be like, hey, hold on.
Hold on right now.
This is this, this is that.
Got to put this away for this.
I love it, man.
Thank you so much, Tavon.
We appreciate that, man.
That is unbelievable.
We just interviewed Tavon Austin.
Tavon Austin, I used to play
with that man's at Madden, bro.
He's been in the NFL for over 10 years, and
he was one of the best returners in all of football.
He's probably got the best college football
highlight tape on the entire planet, man.
Shout out to Tavon Austin.
Over 10 million in one year.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
Well, my graduate degree is in public administration, but
I ended up working in oncology, working in clinical trials.
So I went in a completely different direction.
Are you a business owner?
Yeah, part owner.
And what has been the most amount of
money that you ever made in a single year?
On average, we do, are you
talking about me personally or the business?
I guess both.
The business is 60 million, and
then a couple of million for myself.
Wow.
What's the secret to being able
to scale from six to seven figures?
In business or even just personal
income, what's the secret to scaling?
Well, part of our success is we started a business in late
1990s, and then we sold it for a nice chunk of change.
How much did you sell it for?
365 million.
So you sold a company for 365 million?
Yeah, there was a group of us.
Wow.
So that was really very helpful in terms of making, really gave us an opportunity to sort of
look in a different way and work in an industry that we still enjoy, but in a different way.
So I think if you can create something that's successful,
and then find someone who's going to do it for you,
and then find someone who's interested in
purchasing it, that'd go a long way.
What's the best financial advice that
you've ever received throughout your lifetime?
Invest.
Invest in different companies.
Just have a nice investment plan for yourself.
And you can never start, as they
always say, you can never start too young.
And I think that's true.
And is there a particular industry that you think
people should really be looking to get into right now?
Maybe it's in healthcare, that's a sector that you're in,
or where do you think people should really be looking to?
Well, I think the tech world continues to be a good
part of a successful portfolio, but healthcare definitely, and especially drug development.
And I guess why drug development,
and that sector of healthcare in particular?
Well, because we're just in an exciting phase.
I mean, when I started 22 years ago doing what I'm doing, there
were maybe 12 or 15 good oncology drugs, and now they're over 40.
So there's this real breakthrough that
we've had, especially with immune therapy.
And that'll just continue to move forward.
I love that. Thank you so much for your time.
Thank you. Nice to meet you.
Great to meet you as well.
Good luck with your project.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
My man sold a company for over $360 million.
His company was really good.
Right now, he's doing $60 million a year.
What do you got to
say about Dallas so far, man?
What the fuck?
Dallas has been unreal.
We got Cowboys player Tavon Austin.
We got two major former CEOs.
But my biggest lesson about that last interview is the takeaway that all the money that he's made, the $100 million that he sold
the company for, and the millions that he's bringing home a year, he made it because he did it with a team of people.
Like he said, he didn't just
own all the wealth for himself.
He said, there was a group of us
that came together, and we made something special happen.
They made a shit ton of money doing it.
So if you're out there, you're thinking you could do it alone,
just remember the saying, if you want to go fast, go alone.
But if you want to go far, go together.
Let's go, motherfuckers.
My man right here out in Dallas, he's
parked in the Cullen in the Rolls Royce.
This is a multi-hundred-thousand-dollar
car out in Dallas, Texas.
Let's go up and try
and get this interview real quick.
Excuse me, man.
Quick question for you.
Is this your Rolls Royce?
Yeah, yes, sir.
What do you do for a living?
I own a Sunspot tanning franchise that
has 75 plus locations in 13 states.
And how long have you been a business owner for?
Since 2009.
Is it cool if we
could ask you a few questions?
We go all over the country just
asking business owners their advice to young entrepreneurs.
Yeah.
Is it cool?
Can we ask you a couple
questions outside of the car real quick?
No.
Yes, obviously.
Yeah, yeah, for sure.
Awesome.
Cool.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
Multiple, multiple seven figures.
For someone out there, they're trying to
scale their income from six to seven figures.
What advice would you give them?
The biggest thing is everybody
wants to, people are control freaks.
And there's a really good book.
It's like super short, but it's called Great
CEOs Are Lazy or Good CEOs Are Lazy.
And basically says that if you can delegate and somebody can
do the task 70% as well as you can delegate it.
So, like, I'm a master delegator.
So, I feel like I'm a master.
I find people and I put
them in positions to do things.
Also, the other thing is I also give people opportunities that also benefit myself
in a sense of like I will buy a company and give somebody equity.
So, therefore, that's their baby.
It's an opportunity that they
would have never had previously.
And they're doing 95% of the work.
I use my team and my resources to help
set everything up, you know, the books and all that.
And then that's ways to, you know, essentially it's actually truly, there's
no such thing as passive income, but that's as passive as it gets.
Because that person is doing the work, you're giving them
an opportunity to make more money than they ever would.
And you're benefiting from it as well.
Because, you know, if it's a, say, six-figure profit business
where it's, you know, it's making 600,000, you're 50-50 partners.
Now you're making 300,000.
You're literally doing nothing.
Next thing I was going to ask you is that, you know,
there's a big debate for entrepreneurship, whether they should diversify into different industries.
But do you think entrepreneurs
in today's world, should they diversify?
Or how important has that focus on
one thing been for you throughout your career?
Yeah.
So, this is like an amazing question.
And actually, so, concentration builds wealth, right?
Diversification keeps it.
I don't know whose quote that is,
but I use it all the time.
So, it's like concentrating on one thing.
So, I concentrated on one thing and obviously made enough money where I can,
there's nothing that I see or want to do that I can't afford to do.
So, now what I'm doing is
I'm vertically integrating my whole business.
So, you know, we're constantly, right
now we're building 20 new locations.
So, like this month I'm spending like $200,000 on HVAC.
So, I'm going to buy an HVAC company, an electric
company, a plumbing company, you know, an MEP architectural company.
Because we use so much, you know, the amount of people that are
making money off of us on the real estate commissions and stuff like that.
Also.
I'm building a ton of
commercial buildings, like commercial strips.
And every single one of them
has my business in it, right?
What that does, that's also
vertically integrating and that's diversification.
But it's like, instead of me paying rent
to someone else, I'm paying rent to myself.
So, like that's my sense of diversification.
But when it comes to somebody who is new and like an
entrepreneur, everybody says, oh, we want three streams of income and all that.
That's all just kind of bullshit.
It's like, you know, if you make $1,000 on a rent house
and then you go and have a drop shipping company, you make $1,000.
What is that?
You can literally just focus on one thing.
And kind of scale that up.
And once you have enough cash flow to where you can replace your day job and you can also do
anything you want to go do, then take that money and then diversify into whatever else you want to do.
Yeah.
So.
There you go.
My man.
You crushed that.
Thank you so much.
Appreciate it.
Appreciate it fellas.
Dallas has been one of the craziest
cities that I've shot in so far.
This video has been crazy.
But I want you to comment down below who's
been your favorite person we've interviewed so far and why.
We'd love to connect with you guys.
I want to know all your
thoughts on this video so far.
All right, you guys.
A few months ago, we actually interviewed
a healthcare executive at a $4 billion company.
He was sold.
He's now an angel investor.
But he invited us out to his house in Dallas,
Texas to give us some game to the young entrepreneur.
You're the investor question guy.
Yes, sir.
Good shit, man.
What's your name?
Dante.
Dante James.
Nice to meet you, bro.
Nice to meet you, man.
You do good work.
Appreciate you, man.
Hey, any advice to the younger generation out there?
Oh, man.
I'm not the one to
give advice to the younger generation.
Everybody's got their own perspective.
You know, like if you could
tell anybody any message out there.
What is the biggest life lesson you've ever learned?
The biggest life lesson I've ever learned.
Shit, right now it's to
search peace instead of financial gain.
What would you say is the importance of finding that
peace in yourself as opposed to serving money and serving people?
Well, if you're not right in here, then
whatever you do out here doesn't fucking matter.
Hey, that's some real spill right there.
Dante, appreciate you for stopping by, man.
Have a good one, man.
Have a good one.
Thank you.
You know what?
I love that advice right there.
You can't serve money.
We want to be super successful, but
you got to find that inner peace inside.
If all you're looking for is the
money, you're never going to find peace.
You're never going to find happiness.
That's some real spill right there.
That was a really cool
interaction we just had with Dante.
He recognized us from the channel in
some of the interviews that we had done.
But right now, we're on
the way to the executive's house.
He's going to give us some game on how entrepreneurs can really thrive in
today's business world and what he looks for in companies as an angel investor.
So let's head out right now.
Can't wait to get this content for you guys.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
Healthcare.
In my last role, I was the chief operating
officer for a $700 million business called Health Management Systems.
And did you guys end up selling your company?
We did.
We sold it to a private
equity company for about $3.5 billion.
And it was a very successful
exit at the end of 2020.
That is incredible.
My next question for you.
What was the best financial advice
that you ever received throughout your lifetime?
If you had a mentor or somebody that taught you a lesson about money that
has kind of always stuck with you, what's the best financial advice you ever received?
Spend about half of what you make.
And always keep your powder dry because there's always an
investment that you could use a little bit of money on.
There's always something you could, a person you
can invest in, an idea you can invest in.
And if you don't have any dry powder, we call it
our cash on the sideline, then you're always short of doing that.
So always keep enough cash on the sideline
for any kind of liquid requirements that you have.
And so and I think in this market in
healthcare today, a lot of the valuations have come down.
So over the next two or three years, you're going to see
a multitude of investments that weren't there two to three years ago.
So you should have some money in cash today.
What do you think is the biggest thing that takes
a business from seven to eight and eventually nine figures?
A lot of people don't have a great business idea.
They'll start that business, but
they struggle to scale and grow.
How were you guys able to
scale into a multi-billion dollar business?
I think the biggest challenge was scaling is
just getting enough infrastructure to drive enough business.
Where you need more people, more technology,
you need more sales, you need more marketing,
you need more commercialization of the product and
ultimately you need to make it a industry utility.
So everybody that's not using it is at a disadvantage.
Once you can get to that
tipping point, then you really scale.
What would you say was the biggest
driving factor that really led to your success,
that enabled you to work your way up and become an executive
out of nine and eventually ten figure company in a booming industry?
Helping others succeed.
I think your biggest focus is if you can
help your direct reports get to their next level,
if you can mentor people
on the line, up the ladder.
You can reach down and pull people up the ladder and always
be focused on really giving them constructive criticism on what they did,
what they didn't do, what they could
do, how they should go about it.
Because hiring the best people and lifting them up
always kept me on the top of the food chain.
So that's how I raised.
And so the better you can surround yourself with
great people, the better you can mentor those great people,
the more opportunity you have to
grow in your career as well.
You crushed that. Thank you so much.
Thank you so much for watching this video.
And like it,
subscribe and click here to watch us going all
around Houston asking multimillionaire homeowners how they became successful.